

KIRA LIANG

•

Amsterdam



kiraliang1004@hotmail.com



+31620723404



/kira-liang-2a4a13139

DATA SCIENTIST

PROFILE

I am a self-motivated data scientist with business and natural language processing background. 2 years experiences in interpreting and analyzing data and good knowledge in programming.

I am seeking for a full time job as data scientist/analyst in an organization where I can demonstrate my analytics skills and use my abilities for the growth of the organization along with my personal growth.

SKILLS



EXPERIENCE

NLP INTERN

Elsevier (2019/4 - 2019/6)

- Developed deep learning model that utilized text features to correctly classify multi-labeled scientific articles
- Outperformed the baseline model at 39% with respect to accuracy

DATA ANALYST

Digiwin Software Co., Ltd. (2018/4 - 2018/8)

- Developed insightful metrics, dashboards, reports and insights for the executive team
 - Prediction of retirement: Quantified retirement reasons, reduced employee turnover rate by 12% and reduced business operation cost by 22%
 - Product sales forecast: Gauged product demand and increased inventory turnover rate by 15%

DATA SCIENTIST

ProphetStor Data Services, Inc. (2017/4 - 2018/3)

- Developed conversational flows for chatbots
- Created data pipelining to using the chat conversations to train the AI Bot
- Acquire data from primary or secondary data sources and maintain databases/data systems

EDUCATION

MSC INFORMATION STUDIES: DATA SCIENCE TRACK

University of Amsterdam (2018 - 2019)

 Machine learning, Statistics, Simulation, and Optimization, Data Mining Technics, Information retrieval

DATA ENGINEERING AND DATA ANALYTICS PROGRAM

Institute for Information Industry (2016 - 2017)

• Data Mining and Analytics Technics, Programming (Python, R, JAVA), Big Data (AWS, Hadoop Spark, SQL),

INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS

National ChengChi University (2012 - 2016)

• Statistics, econometrics, marketing, Micro/macro economics, Financial Management

PROJECTS

AUTOMATIC LARGE-SCALE AUDIO ANALYSIS IN US PODCASTS

UvA (2019/3)

• Create a big data architecture to process podcasts data and analyze the gender balance

JOB SEARCH ENGINE

UvA (2019/2)

• Creating a job searching engine using information retrieval techniques.

USER SATISFACTION PREDICTION IN CHATBOT

UvA & ING (2018/12 - 2019/2)

• This project investigates ways to predict user satisfaction, based on the textual conversations of chatbots.

IDENTIFYING DUPLICATE QUESTION PAIRS FOR QUORA

Kaggle in-class challenge, awarded 2nd place (2018/12)

 With feature engineering skill, we generated 30 features from each question pairs and implemented on different machine learning algorithms to classify whether it has the same intent or not.

SENTIMENT ANALYSIS OF 2016 US ELECTION

UvA (2018/9 - 2018/10)

 Using sentiment analysis, topic modeling and network analysis on Twitter data to predict the results of 2016 Presidential Elections.

THEFT CRIME PREDICTION
BASED ON SPATIAL AND
TEMPORAL CRIME
HOTSPOTS

Institute for Information Industry (2017/5 - 2017/7)

 This project aims to find the spatial and temporal theft hotspots in Taipei city by analyzing real-world theft datasets through a statistical analysis and the utility of hotspot mapping.